Guide to the C. Vann Woodward Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1927-2000; Series I
  - S (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 48, Folder 566 - 569)
  - S (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 49, Folder 570 - 575)
  - Saturday Review, 1950-1969 (Box 49, Folder 576)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1953-1998 (Box 49, Folder 577)
  - Scott, Anne Firor, 1951-1998, undated (Box 49, Folder 578)
  - Scott, Foresman and Company, 1958-1971 (Box 50, Folder 579)
  - (Charles) Scribner's Sons, Publishers, 1952-1969 (Box 50, Folder 580)
  - Sellers, Charles G., Jr, 1953-1969 (Box 50, Folder 581)
  - The Sewanee Review, 1987-1995 (Box 50, Folder 582)
  - Shafer, Boyd Carlisle, 1958-1972, undated (Box 50, Folder 583)
  - Shannon, David A., 1949-1969 (Box 50, Folder 584)
  - Shapiro, Herbert, 1964-1968 (Box 50, Folder 585)
  - Sharkey, Robert P., 1948-1977, undated (Box 50, Folder 586)
  - Shimizu, Hiroshi, 1953-1974, undated (Box 50, Folder 587)
  - Shryock, Richard H., 1949-1969 (Box 50, Folder 588)
  - Shugg, Roger W., 1940-1958, undated (Box 50, Folder 589)
  - Silver, James, 1952-1972, undated (Box 50, Folder 590)
  - Simkins, Francis B., 1948-1951 (Box 50, Folder 591)
  - Singal, Daniel J., 1971-1984 (Box 50, Folder 592)
  - Sitterson, J. Carlyle, 1952-1982 (Box 50, Folder 593)
  - Skidmore College, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 594)
  - Sleeper, Jim, 1998-1999, undated (Box 50, Folder 595)
  - Smith, Henry Nash, 1953-1981 (Box 50, Folder 596)
  - Smith, McNeill, 1961-1975 (Box 50, Folder 597)
  - Smith, Wilson, 1958-1998, undated (Box 50, Folder 598)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1953-1969 (Box 50, Folder 599)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 1966-1968 (Box 51, Folder 600)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare, 1938-1940, undated (Box 51, Folder 601)
  - Southern Education Reporting Service, 1954-1968 (Box 51, Folder 602)
  - Southern Historical Association, 1940-1998, undated (Box 51, Folder 603 - 608)
  - Southern Methodist University, 1962-1987 (Box 51, Folder 609)
  - Southern Regional Council, 1958-1985 (Box 51, Folder 610)
  - The Southern Review, 1938-1990 (Box 51, Folder 611)
  - Southgate, Wyndham, 1941-1964 (Box 51, Folder 612)
  - Southwestern at Memphis, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 613)
  - Stampp, Kenneth M., 1951-1978 (Box 52, Folder 614)
  - Stanford University
    - General, 1953-1979, undated (Box 52, Folder 615)
    - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1959-1974, undated (Box 52, Folder 616)
  - State University of Iowa, 1952-1964 (Box 52, Folder 617)
  - State University of New York [includes campuses at Albany, Binghamton, Buffalo, Cortland, Purchase, and Stony Brook], 1963-1974 (Box 52, Folder 618)
  - Stern, Fritz, 1956-1975 (Box 52, Folder 619)
  - Stokely, Wilma Dykeman, 1958-1968 (Box 52, Folder 620)
  - Stone, Olive, 1938-1940, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 621)
  - Strout, Cushing, 1976-1999, undated (Box 52, Folder 622)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, 1963-1966 (Box 52, Folder 623)
  - Studies on the Left, 1960-1967 (Box 52, Folder 624)
  - Studley, Elizabeth S., 1960-1966 (Box 52, Folder 625)
  - Styron, William, 1962-1996, undated (Box 52, Folder 626)
  - T (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 53, Folder 627 - 629)
  - Thornton, Jonathan Mills, III, 1965-1999 (Box 53, Folder 630)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 43
  - Time Magazine, 1938-1981 (Box 53, Folder 631)
  - Tindall, George B., 1955-1995 (Box 53, Folder 632)
  - Todd, Edward N., 1953-1966, undated (Box 53, Folder 633)
  - Toplin, Robert Brent, 1971-1996, undated (Box 53, Folder 634)
  - Toynbee, Arnold J., 1951 (Box 53, Folder 635)
  - Trelease, Allen W., 1961-1970 (Box 53, Folder 636)
  - Turner, Arlin, 1951-1968 (Box 53, Folder 637)
  - U (general), 1953-1993, undated (Box 53, Folder 638)
  - United States
    - General, 1954-1990 (Box 53, Folder 639)
    - Executive departments [includes Departments of Agriculture; Defense; Health, Education, and Welfare; and State], 1950-1974 (Box 54, Folder 640)
    - Military [includes Air Force, Army, and Navy], 1947-1966 (Box 54, Folder 641)
  - Universities, miscellaneous, 1949-1999, undated (Box 54, Folder 642 - 643)
  - University of Alabama [includes general correspondence and University of Alabama Press], 1956-1987 (Box 54, Folder 644)
  - University of Arkansas, 1955-1983 (Box 54, Folder 645)
  - University of California
    - Berkeley, Davis, and Irvine, 1950-1983 (Box 54, Folder 646)
    - Los Angeles, Riverside, San Diego, Santa Barbara, Santa Cruz, and the University of California Press, 1950-1994 (Box 54, Folder 647)
  - University of Cambridge [general], 1975 (Box 54, Folder 648)
  - University of Cape Town [general], 1975-1977 (Box 54, Folder 649)
  - University of Chicago [includes general correspondence and University of Chicago Press], 1948-1981 (Box 54, Folder 650)
  - University of Cincinnati [general], 1959-1969 (Box 54, Folder 651)
  - University of Connecticut [general], 1961-1971 (Box 54, Folder 652)
  - University of Delaware [general], 1952-1978 (Box 55, Folder 653)
  - University of Florida [includes general correspondence and University of Florida Press], 1938-1985 (Box 55, Folder 654)
  - University of Georgia [includes general correspondence and University of Georgia Press], 1949-1997 (Box 55, Folder 655)
  - University of Hawaii [general], 1953-1976 (Box 55, Folder 656)
  - University of Illinois [includes campuses at Chicago and Urbana-Champaign, and University of Illinois Press], 1960-1998 (Box 55, Folder 657)
  - University of Iowa [general], 1949-1976 (Box 55, Folder 658)
  - University of Kansas [general], 1960-1975 (Box 55, Folder 659)
  - University of Kentucky [includes general correspondence and University of Kentucky Press], 1949-1980, undated (Box 55, Folder 660)
  - University of London [includes general correspondence and University College's Commonwealth Lectures], 1953-1976, undated (Box 55, Folder 661)
  - University of Maryland [general], 1952-1988 (Box 55, Folder 662)
  - University of Massachusetts [includes general correspondence and University of Massachusetts Press], 1965-1982 (Box 55, Folder 663)
  - University of Michigan [includes general correspondence and University of Michigan Press], 1952-1977 (Box 55, Folder 664)
  - University of Minnesota [general], 1953-1972 (Box 55, Folder 665)
  - University of Mississippi [includes general correspondence and University of Mississippi Press], 1952-1997 (Box 55, Folder 666)
  - University of Missouri [includes campuses at Columbia and St. Louis, and the University of Missouri Press], 1954-1977, undated (Box 56, Folder 667)
  - University of Nebraska [general], 1949-1975 (Box 56, Folder 668)
  - University of North Carolina
    - General, 1948-1975 (Box 56, Folder 669 - 670)
    - Library, Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina Press, and University of North Carolina Woman's College], 1947-1998, undated (Box 56, Folder 671)
  - University of Oslo [general], 1963-1964 (Box 56, Folder 672)
  - University of Pennsylvania [general], 1954-1993 (Box 56, Folder 673)
  - University of Rochester [general], 1961-1971 (Box 56, Folder 674)
  - University of South Carolina [includes general correspondence, the South Caroliniana Library, and the University of South Carolina Press], 1952-1982, undated (Box 56, Folder 675)
  - University of Southern California [general], 1949-1973 (Box 56, Folder 676)
  - University of Texas [includes campuses at Arlington and Austin], 1948-1983 (Box 56, Folder 677)
  - University of Virginia [includes general correspondence, University of Virginia Press, and the James W. Richards Lectures], 1939-1986, undated (Box 56, Folder 678)
  - University of Washington [includes general correspondence and the University of Washington Press], 1958-1980, undated (Box 56, Folder 679)
  - University of Wisconsin [includes general correspondence and University of Wisconsin Press], 1947-1976 (Box 56, Folder 680)
  - V (general), 1939-1993, undated (Box 57, Folder 681 - 682)
  - Van Auken, Sheldon, 1956-1957 (Box 57, Folder 683)
  - Vance, Rupert B., 1938-1972 (Box 57, Folder 684)
  - Vanderbilt University [includes general correspondence, Vanderbilt University Press, and the Vanderbilt Law Review ], 1949-1983 (Box 57, Folder 685)
  - Van Doren, John, 1957-1959 (Box 57, Folder 686)
  - Van Mameren, Adriaan, 1998-1999 (Box 57, Folder 687)
  - Vann relatives [see also Series VI], 1953-1983, undated (Box 57, Folder 688)
  - Ver Steeg, Clarence L., 1952-1978 (Box 57, Folder 689)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, 1937-1978 (Box 57, Folder 690)
  - W (general), 1938-1998, undated (Box 58, Folder 691 - 697)
  - Wall, Bennett H., 1952-1997 (Box 59, Folder 698)
  - Ward, John William, 1964-1971 (Box 59, Folder 699)
  - Ward, Judson ("Jake"), 1951-1997 (Box 59, Folder 700)
  - Ward, Patricia, 1958-1989, undated (Box 59, Folder 701)
  - Warnell, Willis B., 1955-1965 (Box 59, Folder 702)
  - Warren, Robert Penn and Eleanor, 1954-1985, undated (Box 59, Folder 703)
  - Warren, Rosanna, 1978-1993, undated (Box 59, Folder 704)
  - Washington College, 1956-1973 (Box 59, Folder 705)
  - Washington Post, 1952-1982 (Box 59, Folder 706)
  - Washington University, 1951-1978 (Box 59, Folder 707)
  - Washington, Booker T. (Papers), 1967-1989 (Box 59, Folder 708)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 280
  - Wayne, Michael, 1982-1999 (Box 59, Folder 709)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 46
  - Wayne State University, 1960-1968 (Box 59, Folder 710)
  - Webb, Walter Prescott, 1953 (Box 59, Folder 711)
  - Weinstein, Allen, 1963-1977 (Box 59, Folder 712)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 47
  - Weisberger, Bernard, 1957-1981 (Box 59, Folder 713)
  - Welty, Eudora, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 714)
  - Wesleyan University [includes general correspondence and Wesleyan University Press], 1959-1972 (Box 59, Folder 715)
  - Wheare, Kenneth, 1955-1964, undated (Box 59, Folder 716)
  - Wiebe, Robert, 1967-1977 (Box 59, Folder 717)
  - Wiener, Jonathan, 1974-1989 (Box 59, Folder 718)
  - Wiley, Bell I., 1948-1972, undated (Box 59, Folder 719)
  - William and Mary Quarterly, 1939-1994 (Box 60, Folder 720)
  - Williams, Dudley, 1938-1994 (Box 60, Folder 721)
  - Williams, George Washington, 1956 (Box 60, Folder 722)
  - Williams, John Alexander, 1964-1978 (Box 60, Folder 723)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 49
  - Williams, T. Harry, 1951-1971, undated (Box 60, Folder 724)
  - Williamson, Gustavus G., Jr., 1949-1972, undated (Box 60, Folder 725)
  - Williamson, Joel, 1960-1999 (Box 60, Folder 726)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1969-1978 (Box 60, Folder 727)
  - Winks, Robin M., 1957-1997, undated (Box 60, Folder 728 - 729)
  - Woodward, Comer M. (uncle), 1939-1959 (Box 60, Folder 730)
  - Woodward, Glenn MacLeod (wife), 1937-1960 (Box 60, Folder 731)
  - Woodward, Hugh A. and Bessie Vann (parents), 1930- 1955 (Box 60, Folder 732)
  - Woodward, Lucinda (cousin), 1970 (Box 60, Folder 733)
  - Woodward, Peter Vincent (son), 1965-1969 (Box 60, Folder 734)
  - Woodward, Susan, 1970-1997, undated (Box 60, Folder 735)
  - Wright, Esmond, 1940-1960, undated (Box 60, Folder 736)
  - Wyatt-Brown, Bertram, 1960-1999, undated (Box 61, Folder 737 - 740)
  - Wynes, Charles E., 1956-1979 (Box 61, Folder 741)
  - X (general), 1949, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 742)
  - Y (general), 1953-1999 (Box 61, Folder 743)
  - Yale University
    - General, 1949-1999, undated (Box 61, Folder 744 - 745)
    - Departments/programs [History, African-American Studies, and American Studies], 1957-1995, undated (Box 62, Folder 746)
    - Law School, 1958-1976 (Box 62, Folder 747)
    - Library, 1961-1980 (Box 62, Folder 748)
    - President, Secretary, 1961-1999 (Box 62, Folder 749)
  - Yale University Press, 1959-1997 (Box 62, Folder 750)
  - Yearley, Cliff K., 1954-1966 (Box 62, Folder 751)
  - Young, John, 1952-1954 (Box 62, Folder 752)
  - Younger, Edward, 1954-1960 (Box 62, Folder 753)
  - Z (general), 1939-1997 (Box 62, Folder 754)
  - Unidentified (Box 62, Folder 755 - 757)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1985-1999 (Box 62, Folder 758)
- Writings, 1935-1998; Series II
  The series is arranged in five sections: Short Writings, Books, Book Reviews, Unpublished Writings, and Lectures. Short Writings and Unpublished Writings are the most important because both of them contain unpublished writings. The titles in Short Writings are arranged alphabetically. Those with an asterisk (*) are titles listed in the bibliography in C. Vann Woodward: A Southern Historian and His Critics, by John Herbert Roper (1997). The remaining titles, therefore, were probably never published. When folders in Short Writings contain correspondence, it is often from other historians from whom Woodward asked for critiques. The Unpublished Writings section contains writings that Woodward kept in folders entitled "unpublished", arranged chronologically. Woodward's arrangement has been maintained. The Books and Book Reviews sections are arranged alphabetically by title, and the Lectures section is one folder of promotional material.
  - Short Writings
    - Academic Freedom Crisis in the South, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - The Age of Reinterpretation*
      - General [includes drafts and correspondence], 1959-1960, undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Requests for reprints, 1960, undated (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - The Antislavery Myth* [correspondence only], 1962 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Can We Believe Our Own History?* [issue of Johns Hopkins Magazine ], 1954 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Change Over Time [correspondence and critique only], 1983 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Civil Liberties in War Time [World War II; Scripps College talk], undated (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - The Civil War Among Historians, undated (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - The Comparability of American History*, 1966-1967. undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Comparative History [handwritten draft], undated (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Compromise of 1877 [essay and correspondence; written for the Oxford Companion to United States History ], 1996 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Conditions of a Durable Peace, 1942, undated (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Conference session commentaries, 1960-1995, undated (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Cycles of Academic Freedom, undated (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Defeat [of the South; handwritten draft], undated (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Demagogues [four essays], undated (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Du Bois, W. E. B., undated (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Electronic Technology and the Humanities, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Emancipation and Reconstruction* [correspondence and notes only], 1971, undated (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Emancipation Proclamation, Undated [1963?] (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Failure of Reconstruction [various drafts], undated (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - The Fall of the American Adam [includes correspondence], 1980- 1981, undated (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - The First Reconstruction in the Light of the Second [ includes six of seven Messenger lectures at Cornell University], 1964 (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - Fitzhugh, George [writings by others and correspondence only], 1959, undated (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - The Future is the Past [correspondence and research materials only], 1970-1988, undated (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - Genovese, Aptheker, and Heresy, undated (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - Harper Ferry's Raid [correspondence only], 1950, undated (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - Hendricks College [short, autobiographical remarks], 1997 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - Hillbilly Realism*, undated (Box 64, Folder 29)
    - Historiography and Historians [various writings and notes], 1970, undated (Box 64, Folder 30)
    - Irony III [re: follow-up to 1952 Southern Historical Association presidential address], 1969, 1991-1992, undated (Box 64, Folder 31 - 33)
    - Lectures I -VIII [The South as an Approach to the American Legend; From Slavery to Caste: Origins of American Racism; From Liberalism to Conformity: Southern Response to Abolitionism; From Propaganda to Armed Conflict: Psychology of Civil War Crisis; From 'Conquered Province' to 'Home Rule': Strategy of Reconstruction; Compromise and Diplomacy of Reunion; Politics and Rituals of Reconciliation; From Commonwealth to Colony: Subordination of the South], undated (Box 64, Folder 34)
    - Little Rock [speech given there; correpondence only], 1961 (Box 64, Folder 35)
    - Mary Chesnut [for Encyclopedia of Slavery ], 1997 (Box 64, Folder 36)
    - The Negro in America [for the Associated Press], 1940 (Box 64, Folder 37)
    - Notable books, undated (Box 64, Folder 38)
    - The Old World's New World [revised manuscript], 1991, undated (Box 65, Folder 39)
    - On the Obsolescence of the 'New South', 1961, undated (Box 65, Folder 40)
    - Overrated Presidents, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 41)
    - Plessy vs. Ferguson [notes and correspondence only], 1961-1963, undated (Box 65, Folder 42)
    - The Political Philosophy of Tom Watson and the Usable Past [Academy of Social Sciences, Atlanta, Georgia], 1938 (Box 65, Folder 43)
    - Prefaces, introductions, undated (Box 65, Folder 44)
    - Psychohistory and Quantohistory [includes Letter from the World of Historians; and What's New in History?], 1975-1976, undated (Box 65, Folder 45)
    - Quantification Reflections, undated (Box 65, Folder 46)
    - Reagan, Ronald, and Bush, George, undated (Box 65, Folder 47)
    - Reflections on American Democracy [for Encyclopedia Americana, includes correspondence], 1990-1991, undated (Box 65, Folder 48)
    - The Role of Universities in Desegregation: The American South [paper for conference in South Africa], 1975-1976, undated (Box 65, Folder 49)
    - Share the Wealth; Townsend Plan [for Dictionary of American History ], undated (Box 65, Folder 50)
    - Silvers, Bob and the New York Review of Books, undated (Box 65, Folder 51)
    - Slavery and the Intellectual, part IV, undated (Box 65, Folder 52)
    - Sources of Southern History*, undated (Box 65, Folder 53)
    - The South, Then and Now [given at Wake Forest University symposium on W. J. Cash; includes comments by Morrison and Genovese], 1991, undated (Box 65, Folder 54)
    - The South in Search of a Philosophy* [Phi Beta Kappa address, Gainesville, Florida], 1938 (Box 65, Folder 55)
    - The South Old and New [for conference on the American South in Belgium], 1985 (Box 65, Folder 56)
    - South Winds of Doctrine, undated (Box 65, Folder 57)
    - The Southern Ethic* [includes comments of others], 1967-1968, undated (Box 66, Folder 58)
    - Southern Exiles [Fleming lectures], undated (Box 66, Folder 59)
    - Southern Distinctiveness, undated (Box 66, Folder 60)
    - The Southern Heritage of Tennesee Williams, undated (Box 66, Folder 61)
    - The Southern Historian and his Subject, undated (Box 66, Folder 62)
    - Southern History and American Legend [University College London; typescripts of seven of eight lectures], 1954 (Box 66, Folder 63)
    - A Southern Perspective, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 64)
    - The Status of History in the Schools, 1975, undated (Box 66, Folder 65)
    - Storr lectures [Slavery to Freedom; Comparative Approach to Emancipation History; Comparative Approach to Reconstruction History], 1969 (Box 66, Folder 66)
    - Strange Career Critics: Long May They Persevere* [ Journal of American History reprint], 1988 (Box 66, Folder 67)
    - Teaching of American History in Public Schools, undated (Box 66, Folder 68)
    - Thomas Watson* [for the Dictionary of American Biography ], undated (Box 66, Folder 69)
    - Those Southern Folkways, undated (Box 66, Folder 70)
    - The Time Has Come the Walrus Said
      See: Series III. Subjects, 1947-1997 Folder 56
    - Tributes to individuals [Beale, Brooks, Carleton, Frankel, Gay, Hackney, Hofstadter, McFeely, Sanford, Warren, Webb], undated (Box 66, Folder 71)
    - Universities and Democracies [several handwritten drafts, correspondence, collected materials], 1969-1991, undated (Box 67, Folder 72 - 73)
    - University Vicissitudes [University of Pennsylvania inaugural address], 1981 (Box 67, Folder 74)
    - The West and South Compared as Competitors [Western Historical Association panel remarks], 1992 (Box 67, Folder 75)
    - Wilderness in Canaan, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 76)
    - William and Mary commencement address, 1964 (Box 67, Folder 77)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 67, Folder 78)
      Unidentified manuscript and typescript fragments, including the first page of chapter 17 of an unidentified work, titled "The West as a Built-in Empire."
  - Books
    - American Counterpoint, 1970-1972 (Box 68, Folder 79)
    - The Battle for Leyte Gulf [correspondence], 1945-1947, 1959, undated (Box 68, Folder 80)
    - The Burden of Southern History, 1958-1961 (Box 68, Folder 81)
    - The Comparative Approach to American History [mostly correspondence and new introduction], 1995-1997 (Box 68, Folder 82)
    - The Future of the Past [correspondence, outline, draft], 1969, 1988-1990, undated (Box 68, Folder 83)
    - History of the United States [proposed book?], undated (Box 68, Folder 84)
    - Mary Chesnut's Civil War
      - Correspondence
        - Chesnut heirs, 1973-1981, n.d (Box 69, Folder 85)
        - Mertz, Mrs. Arthur, 1964 (Box 69, Folder 86)
        - Muhlenfeld, Elizabeth, 1945-1981, undated (Box 69, Folder 87 - 89)
        - Congratulations and thank yous, 1981, undated (Box 69, Folder 90)
      - Copyright, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 91)
      - Editing of the diary, 1960-1982, undated (Box 69, Folder 92 - 94)
      - National Historical Publications and Records Commission [re: grant], 1976-1987, undated (Box 70, Folder 95 - 96)
      - Photographs [for the book and of Woodward], 1981, undated (Box 70, Folder 97)
      - Public television, 1983 (Box 70, Folder 98)
      - Publicity brochure, 1981 (Box 70, Folder 99)
      - Textual integrity, 1981, undated (Box 70, Folder 100)
    - The National Experience [miscellaneous insertions], undated (Box 70, Folder 101)
    - The Origins of the New South [correspondence], 1939-1952, undated (Box 70, Folder 102 - 103)
    - Paradoxes of American race [materials regarding proposed book and why Woodward decided not to write it], 1994-1995 (Box 70, Folder 104 - 107)
    - Reconstruction [regarding proposed book], 1947-1981 (Box 71, Folder 108)
    - Reunion and Reaction, 1949-1951, undated (Box 71, Folder 109)
    - Seventh grade history book [correspondence with Harcourt, Brace], 1952-1954 (Box 71, Folder 110)
    - The Southerner as American, 1953-1957, undated (Box 71, Folder 111)
    - Strange Career of Jim Crow
      - Revised paperback edition, 1956-1957 (Box 71, Folder 112)
      - Royalties, 1959-1960 (Box 71, Folder 113)
    - Thinking Back [correspondence], 1984-1986 (Box 71, Folder 114)
    - Tom Watson: Agrarian Rebel [correspondence], 1938, undated (Box 71, Folder 115)
  - Book Reviews
    - General, 1935-1978, undated (Box 71, Folder 116 - 118)
    - D'souza, Dinesh, Illiberal Education, 1983-1993, undated (Box 72, Folder 119 - 123)
    - Johnson, Lyndon Baines [reviews of biographies for New York Review of Books], 1990-1991 (Box 72, Folder 124)
  - Unpublished Writings
    - n.d.
      - History and Version Thereof (Box 73, Folder 125)
      - Living with Lost Causes (Box 73, Folder 125)
      - The Negro in America (Box 73, Folder 125)
      - Of Arms and Men (Box 73, Folder 125)
      - Perspectives for Southern Historians (Box 73, Folder 125)
      - The South: Old and New-A Century of American Historiography (Box 73, Folder 125)
      - Southern Past in Southern Fiction (Box 73, Folder 125)
      - Toward a Definition of the South (Box 73, Folder 125)
    - 1950s
      - The Abraham Lincoln Industry (Box 73, Folder 126)
      - American Historiography, 1930-1953 (Box 73, Folder 126)